EMILY WEYDA // Software Engineer

Diligent recent college graduate with a Bachelor of Science (B.S.) in Computer Engineering and Minor in Computer Science, with 2+ years of work experience. Aiming to leverage academic experience and a proven knowledge of research and development, product design, and prototype to successfully fill the Software Engineer role at your company.

www.emilyweyda.com emily.weyda@gmail.com github.com/weydaej linkedin.com/in/emilyweyda

513 429 9368





Education

University of Cincinnati // Class of 2020

♀ Cincinnati, OH // CUM GPA 3.34, EECE GPA 3.51 College of Engineering and Applied Science Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering Minor in Computer Science

University of Birmingham // Fall 2018

P Birmingham, England // Study Abroad School of Computer Science, First Class Honours



Technical Skills

Languages: Python • Java • C/C++ • C#/.NET • JavaScript • HTML • CSS • Swift • SQL • MATLAB

Software/Platforms: Git/GitHub • Docker • Anaconda • SQL Server • OS X • Windows • Unix



Projects

Processing & Updating Position in Python

A deep learning model designed to process accelerometer and gyroscope data from a smartphone to predict a user's motion.

Tic-Tac-Toe

Two player Java CLI tic-tac-toe game.

Brick Breaker

Python version of the classic arcade game "Breakout" using the pygame library.

Flappy Tina

Bob's Burgers themed "Flappy Bird" game written in Swift that implements physics for accurate interactions between components.

Battleship

Battleship game written in MATLAB that implements a smart AI capable of beating a human player.



🚰 Leadership

Robotics Club // Mentor

Butler Tech | August 2017 - May 2019

ACM-W // Member

University of Cincinnati | November 2015 - May 2020

Bearcat Coders // Volunteer

Hughes High School | November 2015 - September 2018

Girl Scouts of America // Scout & Troop Co-leader Cincinnati, OH | August 2003 - December 2018

Professional Experience

R&D Software Engineer // Siemens Software Internship Milford, OH // January 2019 - August 2019

- Explored cutting edge technologies to deliver proof of concept projects utilizing Google AutoML, Google Cloud Platform, Docker, RESTful APIs and Node.js
- Conducted research on several different machine learning methodologies, quantum computing and natural language processing
- Implemented and improved on existing machine learning tools developed for complete data preprocessing, training, and deploying of accurate machine learning models
- Developed a conversational interface for 3D modeling using Siemens NX and Google Dialogflow

Cyber Software Engineer // ICR, Inc. Internship

♀ Mason, OH // January 2018 - May 2018

- Added capability to assess GitLab Continuous Integration (CI) tests post-merge using webhooks and **RESTful APIs**
- Implemented functionality to GitLab CI for improved communication between teams using Slack Notifications Service utilizing incoming webhooks integration
- Emulated Raspberry Pi using QEMU, debugging with GDB-GEF and utilized the command line and Binary Ninja to reverse ARM binaries
- Self-taught ARM assembly basics and gained experience within the realm of ARM exploit development

R&D Software Engineer // Honeywell Intelligrated Internship **♀** Mason, OH // August 2016 - August 2017

- Utilized C#/.NET, Microsoft SQL Server, XML, and WinForms to develop internal research and development tools
- Contributed to an Agile Scrum development team by designing software solutions that drove continuous improvement to applications that allow Intelligrated engineers to better develop hardware and software products for clients
- Starting with a broken application, led the effort to build a feature that allows users to view, mark up, sort and export log files and managed the deployment of this software release
- Designed, wrote, and tested new features for a tool currently being used by internal software engineers working on the solutions driving the warehouse execution systems